The radiance of the night shines through my window
but the path to immortality is long.
The Eight Views and Nine-Bend Streams are desolate.
Living beings question the miseries of the world over a jar of wine.
Forget about Nirvana and rebirth,
I will break through the waves with my own flesh and blood.
The heavens are vast, so what if I was born mediocre ?
I stare at the Dao in my moments of madness
as the storm rages just below.
I've been thinking about life and death in my dreams.
I've unsheathed my sword to ask the immortals
why the world is a-changing.
Heaven and earth reveals its poignant truths.
Swallow the Four Seas and the Eight Wastelands,
experience all the vicissitudes of life in an instant.
I will defy the light in the sky
to continue to write a new chapter for all things in the three realms of existence.
Just a thought separates mortal from immortal.
Transform your insignificant body into light.
The hardships of the journey
will temper this young man's heart.
If I become a Renegade Immortal, will I hesitate to fight the heavens ?
Renegade Immortal
Subtitles by Bonobosubs
https://discord.gg/Ceckd4pdVA
Among my 7 divisions of the Heavenly Fate Sect,
the Yellow and Violet divisions
still don't have Sons of Tian Yun.
Today is the day of the competition
for the Seven Sons of Tian Yun.
Are you all
ready to begin ?
The sect is flourishing
and its disciples are powerful.
But with the Heavenly Fate Sect's heritage,
how is it possible that not a single disciple has surpassed Ascendant ?
Disciple' cultivation is too shallow
and insufficient to compete with my Senior Brothers for the title.
Disciple gives up.
Disciple still needs to cultivate diligently.
Disciple is ashamed to give up.
Disciple forfeits.
Disciple isn't strong enough to compete.
Thanks to all my previous efforts
building relationships with other fellow disciples,
even Senior Brother agreed to yield to me.
Today, I will finally become
a Son of Tian Yun.
The Seven Sons of Tian Yun's status is sky high,
they even have a chance to receive a celestial spell.
Why would these disciples give up so easily ?
Yun Daozi ?
Master,
Second Junior Brother’s cultivation is profound
and he was just given a celestial artifact by Master.
He rightfully should become the Yellow Division's Son of Tian Yun.
Disciple wishes to forfeit
to protect my Second Junior Brother's Dao.
The Seven Sons of Tian Yun
are titles within our Heavenly Fate Sect
and also the name of my true direct disciples.
If you can maintain the title for a 1000 years,
Master
will teach you a celestial spell.
Kunpeng Zi,
you
should prepare yourself.
Disciple humbly follows your teachings.
I will not disgrace the name of Tian Yun.
Cultivate in seclusion
to understand this item.
Those with formidable strength don’t compete for the title.
They make everyone else fear them.
Thank you, Master.
Is there more than meets the eye
to this Son of Tian Yun title ?
Next up
is our Purple Division's
competition to decide the Son of Tian Yun.
Wang Lin,
Zhao Xinmeng,
Bai Wei,
are you three
ready to begin ?
Disciple gives up.
Seventh Brother...
If I give up too,
it would be too easy for you to obtain the title.
You and I shall fight
right here, right now.
Fourth Senior Sister never competed for the title before.
Why is she now challenging me now ?
If I have doubts about the Seven Sons of Tian Yun,
she must also have the same doubts.
Disciple
gives up.
Why are you giving up ?
Disciple’s cultivation is too low.
I'm unable to compete with Fourth Senior Sister.
Wang Lin !
Disciple' cultivation is too shallow
and insufficient to compete with my Senior Brothers for the title.
Disciple isn't strong enough to compete.
Disciple is ashamed to give up.
...to protect my Second Junior Brother's Dao.
That feeling just now
was as if everything about me
was laid bare before him.
My disciples
shouldn't be cowards.
You shouldn't be bewitched by others
and should follow your desires.
I'll give you half an incense stick of time
to think about it carefully.
If you still decide to give up,
I won't stop you.
Master always lets disciples choose.
Why is he advising him today ?
Since Sun Yun,
the only disciple Master advised
is this Wang Lin.
Defying the All-Seer now is unwise.
Even if something's wrong about the Seven Sons of Tian Yun,
this duel
is unavoidable.
Disciple
will try his best.
Seventh Brother,
let's begin.
My Dao is
the Demon's Shadow.
As long as I see a spell once
and its requirements are not beyond my cultivation,
I can imitate a weaker version of it.
This spell
is my imitation of
the Demonic Finger you used before.
I call it
the Purple Demonic Hand !
Demonic Finger !
What an amazing demonic energy !
My Demon's Shadow imitation is still somewhat lacking.
Seventh Brother,
I won’t compete with you for the Son of Tian Yun title.
But this demonic energy
must be mine.
Senior Sister went to such lengths
to lure me into using the Demonic Finger
just to obtain its demonic energy.
If you had asked me directly,
Junior Brother might not have minded.
But now,
I won't let you
steal it !
Seventh Brother,
I just want a bit of your demonic energy.
This is very important for me.
If you agree,
I’ll give up immediately.
Otherwise...
I can't grant you
this favor.
Alright,
if you don’t use your Demonic Finger,
I wonder how long you'll last.
The Nine Cycle Celestial Refining Tactic ?
This spell is extremely difficult to cultivate
and I just gave him the jade slip.
How could he possibly
have already mastered it !?
Junior Brother,
your three cycles
are useless against me !
Now...
it’s five cycles !
This child...
Is he really a fit for my Dao ?
Back then,
he left me with a single phrase.
"My Dao
is the Dao of Heavenly Fate."
Only by finding people who fit my Dao
will I have a chance to enter the third step.
It's been more than 30 000 years
and I’ve already failed countless times.
Am I
doing it right ?
Am I wrong ?
Do you still want to see
my Nine Cycle Celestial Refining Tactic's strength ?
I really underestimated you.
Seventh Brother,
I give up.
Even Senior Sister Xinmeng couldn’t defeat him ?
Wang Lin is exceptionally talented.
The Son of Tian Yun
will be given to the new disciple ?
Indeed...
I'm so jealous !
When will we become Sons of Tian Yun ?
Such momentum...
This person’s cultivation
must be Ascendant.
Disciple Chen Tao
pays respects to Master.
Chen Tao
Heavenly Fate Sect
Purple Division disciple
Middle stage Ascendant
Chen Tao ?
If Sun Yun hadn't suddenly emerged back then,
the Purple Division's Son of Tian Yun
would likely still be Chen Tao.
You made it back in time,
very good !
Disciple originally wasn't going to be late
but when I passed planet Black Ink,
I saw a rare treasure there.
Disciple took a liking to it
and wished to gift it to Master.
That's why I was delayed.
What kind of treasure
caught your eye ?
Disciple found this on planet Black Ink,
3 high-quality Desolate Beasts were fighting over it.
Disciple was curious, so I took it.
Unfortunately, my knowledge is limited.
I don't know
what it is exactly.
This flower is called the Seven-Colored Glaze.
It takes 10 years to take root,
100 years to make leaves,
1000 years to make a bud,
10 000 years
for it to bloom.
After it blooms 7 times,
it releases a 7-colored light.
The Cultivation Alliance
ranks this item
as the 93rd heavenly treasure.
Elder Sun,
is this old man correct ?
That is correct.
This is indeed a Seven-Colored Glaze.
Senior All-Seer’s outstanding disciples
are truly a breath of fresh air.
Good...
I will
accept your gift.
Master,
disciple has returned
to reclaim the title of Son of Tian Yun.
I humbly ask for Master’s blessing.
The victor between you two
shall be the Purple Division's Son of Tian Yun.
You
should give up !
This isn't how
this spell should be used.
Only in the hands of an Ascendant cultivator
can this spell truly be called
the Nine Cycle Celestial Refining Tactic.
With such a low cultivation,
you're unworthy of being my Seventh Junior Brother !
Teleportation !
Teleportation
to turn his spell against him ?
That's a clever way to fight an Ascendant.
Those kinds of tricks won't change anything.
Are you trying to outsmart me ?
It's useless !
Beast Soul,
come out !
Devour him !
You snarling beast,
come and play with me !
God Slaying Chariot,
fifth seal,
release !
This is...
Interesting...
This fight against an Ascendant allows me
to use Chen Tao's strength to fight the Beast Soul
and lessens the backlash from undoing the seal.
That was my best opportunity to open the seal.
When I release
all 5 seals on this beast,
I wonder how powerful
the God Slaying Chariot will be.
Good !
Very good !
If you can subdue this beast,
then you're qualified to be my Junior Brother !
You
are not yet qualified to be my Senior Brother.
I'll take the time to fight this beast
and then I'll deal with you.
It doesn't change anything.
We will see
if I’m qualified !
Wang Lin,
do you dare to take my strike ?
Why would I not ?
This final killing spell has immense backlash.
Use it responsibly
before Late stage Soul Transformation.
You must wait until Ascendant
before you can use it freely.
Under...
world...
Finger !
This finger...
Why is it the same as that madman's
that I met earlier ?
The Life and Death Reincarnation Cycle Domain....
Here it comes !
He's only Soul Transformation
and he's able to push an Ascendant this far !
That's enough.
Master,
disciple gives up.
When you reach Ascendant,
we shall fight again,
Seventh Brother.
You are both my disciples,
don't be jealous of each other.
Chen Tao,
since you won
you shall be once more
the Purple Division's Son of Tian Yun.
This is not your first time receiving the title,
take your time to comprehend it.
Thank you, Master.
Now I'm sure that there is something else
to the Seven Sons of Tian Yun.
Before I learn what that crystal is,
I mustn't become one.
Fortunately, Chen Tao returned.
Since I fought an Ascendant with all I have,
I avoided offending the All-Seer
and avoided becoming a Son of Tian Yun.
Esteemed guests,
this is the end of this old man's birthday.
Fellow cultivators, if you don't have urgent matters,
please stay at my Heavenly Fate Sect for a few more days
to discuss the Dao
and share our enlightenments.
Farewell, Senior All-Seer.
Wang Lin,
come with me to pay respects to the Ancestral Spirit.
Afterward, I will teach you a forbidden spell and give you a life-saving artifact.
From now on,
you officially become
my disciple.
Thank you, Master.
"I always decide which
forbidden spell each student will learn, but if you can see through
the mysteries of this mountain, Master will break the rules and
let you choose whichever spell you want."
Three Black and White Peaks
Heavenly Fate Sect
Wang Lin,
what do you think of this place ?
This place is rich in cold Yin energy.
It's a great place to cultivate cold-type techniques.
Is that all ?
This mountain is completely black.
Even the snow falling on it is black.
However, this black snow isn't cold, it gives off a strange aura.
The central mountain's aura
is even stranger.
Oh ?
Continue.
This mountain is so strange
because I can sense
a hint of Life from it.
Although all beings possess Life energy,
it's the first time
that I have seen a mountain
with Life energy.
Is that all ?
It's not enough.
Master,
those two side mountains are fake.
This child's intellect is exceptional
and his domain is quite interesting.
He was able to use his domain
to see through my spell.
Detecting such clues with his Soul Transformation cultivation
is pretty impressive.
The All-Seer's cultivation is heavenly.
If not for Tu Si's memories
I wouldn't have seen the truth behind these mountains.
Judging from the All-Seer's reaction,
maybe...
he doesn't know that I have memories of an Ancient God.
Wang Lin,
Master will wait for you at the summit.
The first 100 steps will be easy
with your Soul Transformation cultivation.
But the final 100 steps to the summit
will depend on your fate.
Those final 100 steps
are what Master calls
the Shattered Land of the Celestials.
I've been walking this path for endless years
just to catch a glimpse of your silhouette.
Is it the compass of fate
that wrote this outcome for us ?
The heavens want to erase your existence,
that's the obsession guiding me.
Is this the path to uncover
truths from falsehoods ?
In a world of murk and shadow,
only the flame of truth can light the way.
Look at them all,
being carried by the waves.
being drowned.
I don't want to believe in whoever decides fate,
I will let the world refine my soul.
So what if I become an Immortal and defy the heavens ?
I will fight.
I'll break through the abyss of despair
to finally learn who I really am.
My body is stained by the bloody color of slaughter,
I embrace this obsession.
I won't glance back at the wasteland I left behind.
Even if this suffering shatters my soul
and I'm reborn countless times in hell,
I'll still fight.
It's hard to avoid loneliness
when you are above everyone else.
Can a moth that has witnessed the flames of a Suzaku
be afraid of a firefly ?